Guide to the Walter and Martha Leuba Papers, 1735-1988 SC.1988.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Personal Papers, 1868-1988; 1914-1988; V.
  - Biography and Genealogy, 1868-1980; 1917-1980; 2.
    - Genealogy Notes, 1935-1980 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Oral Interview with Walter Leuba by Lawrence Howard, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Official Documents, 1914-1986; 3.
    Subseries contains a range of medical, financial, and professional documents related to Walter, Martha, and Mildred Leuba, including birth, marriage, and death certificates. Additional vital records related to members of the extended Leuba family were collected by Leuba in separate genealogy files and can be found in Subseries 2 (Biography and Genealogy). Oversize items have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this Subseries.
    - Department of Public Assistance Certificates - Martha Leuba, 1944 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Mildred Leuba - Death, 1932-1944 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Social Security, Retirement, and Misc., 1925-1968 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Financial, Retirement, and Misc., 1954-1969 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - 516 Jacksonia Payments, 1947-1955 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 516 Jacksonia - Insurance and Assessment, 1979-1985 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Personal Documents - Passports, Diplomas, Misc., 1925-1948 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Financial, Medical, and Misc., 1945-1975 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Medical, Insurance and Real Estate Tax Documents, 1948-1978 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Real Estate Tax Documents, 1970-1985 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Documents - wills, funeral arrangements for Walter and Martha Leuba, 1958-1986 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Documents – Walter Leuba death certificate, misc., 1914-1985 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Documents - medical, home appliance contracts, 1939-1949 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Documents - 516 Jacksonia deeds, birth and marriage certificates, 1925- 1962 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Oversize - Martha Dryburgh, Pittsburgh High Schools diploma, 1925 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Oversize - Martha Dryburgh, B.S. diploma, University of Pittsburgh, 1930 (Box 64, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1899-1984; VI.
  Series consists of albums, loose, and framed photos. Albums cover a range of subjects, including groups of family photos and albums documenting places and homes (516 Jacksonia in particular). Bulk of the materials are undated; dates are provided where available. Oversize items have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this Series.
  - Photo Album [Samuel Leuba], 1900-1959 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album [Martha and Walter Leuba], 1967-1978 (Box 50, Folder 2-3)
  - Photo Album (1 of 2), 1923-1967 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Photo Album (2 of 2), 1923-1967 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album [Leuba Family], 1899-1962 (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
  - Photo Album [516 Jacksonia and other places], 1925, 1949-1966 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Photo Album [516 Jacksonia], 1949-1951 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album [Harald Leuba and Family], 1926-1959 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Photo Album [Chris and Mildred Leuba], 1911-1975 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Album of Snapshots [Garden, Family, and Misc.] (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Panorama Brand Index Photo Album [Family and misc.], 1946-1961 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Bentley, Wilder (The Acorn Press), 1934 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Poems of Walter Leuba Window Display - Prints and Slides, circa 1965-1968 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Walter Leuba, Book Exhibit, and Other People (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - McCulloughs and Leubas - family events, 1973-1984 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Leuba Family and Others (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - 516 Jacksonia - Taken by Dick Edwards (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Loose Photographs (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Loose Photographs, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Framed - Haniel Long, by Ernest Knee (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Framed - Hans Otto Storm (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Framed and signed Carte-de-visite, I[J?] A. F[unds?] (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Framed - Portrait, man in uniform (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Framed - Photos and Silhouette of Children (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Framed - Family portraits (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Framed - Miniature and small photos (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Negatives - Canal Book, circa 1954 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Negatives - Walter Leuba (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Negatives [5x7], circa 1927 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Negatives (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Negatives (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Oversize Photographs of Walter Leuba (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Oversize Landscape and Flower Photographs (Box 64, Folder 3)
- Scrapbooks, 1838-1980; 1918-1980; VII.
  Series includes bound scrapbook volumes and loose scrapbook pages, circa 1918 - 1980 (bulk undated). The bulk of the material consists of newspaper clippings about literary topics. Loose clippings are inserted between the covers and pages of most scrapbooks. Other pages include collections of dried leaves, photographs, and concert programs, and other items. Oversize items have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this series. Additional scrapbook volumes of correspondence can be found in Series II, Subseries 3 (Correspondence with Mildred Leuba).
  - Bound Literary Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1934–1946 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Bound Literary Clippings - Austen, Johnston and others, circa 1939-1946 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Bound Clippings Scrapbook - Obituaries, Poems, etc., circa 1926–1979 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Dried Leaves - Press Book (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Bound Scrapbook of Clippings, circa 1957–circa 1980 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Bound Scrapbook of Clippings, 1838-1976 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Includes m.s. and published poems by Walter Leuba
  - Concert and Recital Programs, circa 1918–circa 1946 (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - Theatre Program Scrapbook pages, 1923-1937 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Bound Literary Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1933 - circa 1945 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Bound Literary Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1934 - circa 1945 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Bound Literary Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1946 – circa 1947 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Bound Literary Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1946 - circa 1947 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Bound Gardening Scrapbook, circa 1948- circa 1950 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Bound Art, Woodcut and Book Plates Scrapbook (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Oversize Scrapbooks, circa 1929-1937 (Box 60, Volume 1-2)
- Ephemera, 1890-1973; 1922-1973; VIII.
  Series contains clippings and printed matter related to Leuba's collecting activities, event programs, announcements, and other ephemera. Bulk of items are undated; dates are provided where available.
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1948-1959, 1970-1971 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Events and Announcements, 1947-1973 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Youth Symphony Program and Review of Chris Leuba, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Calligraphy Practice, with instructor notes, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - P. Duschnes private printing, Two Chapters from an Unfinished Autobiography: Confessions of a Dealer in Rare Books, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Advertisements, 1893 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - International Poetry Forum Program, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Music Programs, 1925-1943 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Bibliophiles Meeting Announcements and Invitations, 1964-1973 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Programs and invitations, 1890-1968 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Postage stamps, 1951-1952, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Long, Haniel, 1922-1965 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Long, Haniel, 1924-1937 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - US and PA maps, 1939 and undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Limited Editions Club newsletter, 1929-1930 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Articles and newspapers, 1953-1972 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Framed newsclipping - Inscribed for Mildred by Eli Siegel, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 12)
- Woodblocks, IX.
  Consists of 6 woodblocks and related items. Includes a linoleum block of Leuba's home (516 Jacksonia Street) and various other patterns.
  - 516 Jacksonia linoleum block (Box 62, Item 1)
  - Large paisley design woodblock (Box 62, Item 2)
  - Two leaf pattern woodblocks (Box 62, Item 3-4)
  - Asian characters woodblock and print (Box 62, Item 5)
  - Woodblock roller (Box 62, Item 6)